- Who is this bloke? - He's just a man, Colin.
翻译    哈里不是波特   melanie_je
Thank you. The guv'nor wants a word.
谢谢  老大有话要说
Two weeks after coming so close, I suspect,
在与成功失之交臂两周后  我猜测
oh, sod that, I know, cos I've heard you,
算了  我知道  因为我听到你们聊天了
some of you reckon he's gone to ground
有些同事认为他已经再次隐匿
and this is just a big, expensive waste of time.
所以现在的做法是完全彻底的浪费时间
OK, the near-miss might've spooked him into packing up,
我们那次失手确实可能吓得他更加谨慎
I concede that.
这点我承认
But I take a different view.
但我不认为他会停手
I think it'll drive him back into operating in the one place
我觉得这会让他回到  我们知道他自认为
we know he feels safe.
安全的地方
Our key lead remains the grey Zafira
我们的关键线索仍然是那辆灰色赛飞利
and I know you all know that
这一点你们也了然于胸
but take another look at these different angles.
但请大家再从不同角度仔细看一下这辆车
Imprint them on your brain,
将它们刻入脑海
so that at a glance, or from a distance,
这样你们哪怕在远距离
you can clock it.
也能一眼锁定它
Thank you very much.
非常感谢大家
- 34. - Cheers, Nath.
-34号  -谢谢  内森
- There you go. - Thanks, Nath.
-给你  -谢谢  内森
- Bring it back in one piece... - Are you all right, guv?
-要完好的拿回来...  -你没事吧  老大
Well, you've seen it at Central 3000,
你在中央3000监控系统也看到了
after midnight nothing happens.
午夜之后毫无动静
Foxes and a few inquisitive cats,
只有狐狸和一些好奇的猫
that's the extent of the action.
夜里的动态也就如此而已
I am genuinely worried they're gonna start nodding off.
我真的很担心他们会开始打瞌睡
- No way, boss. - Or they get so used to nothing happening
-不可能  老大  -或者他们习惯了无事发生
they don't clock it when it does.
而不会在有情况时候及时发现
- Well, I just can't see that. - Why not?
-我觉得不可能  -怎么不可能
Very first night, he drove right through the plot.
第一天晚上  他就在区域内径直开了过去
We didn't know he drove a Zafira then.
当时我们不知道他开一辆赛飞利
How many vehicles went through that night? Five?
那晚总共才几辆车开过  五辆吗
They could've at least got a reg!
他们最起码应该看到车牌
With respect, Sir, that's harsh.
无意冒犯  长官  但这有些苛刻了
Clocking the number plate from an OP
监控点的位置  在漆黑的夜里
- and in the dark isn't exactly easy. - Yeah, you're right, Neville.
-看清车牌并不容易  -你说的也是  内维尔
I just want to get him before they pull the plug on us.
我只想在他停手之前抓到他
- You think that's imminent? - I don't know.
-你觉得能很快做到吗  -我不知道
Come on.
跟我来
Central 3000 will manage for one night without us.
今晚没有我们  中央3000监控系统也不会有问题
'OP3 in position.'
3号监控点就位
'OP44 in position.'
44号监控点就位
'OP32 in position.'
32号监控点就位
'OP27 in position.'
27号监控点就位
We weren't expecting such august company, Sir.
我们没预到会有这么高级别人来现场  长官
Oh, well, we don't want any fuss, just want to see how it's done.
我们不想大肆宣扬  只想来看看你们怎么工作
- This way. - Thank you.
-这边走  -谢谢
Actually, we're down an OP tonight
其实今晚我们少一个监控员
- it's good to have you. - Evening.
-有你们帮忙正好  -晚上好
We'll bring you a cuppa for when the curtain goes up.
等窗帘拉上后我们会给你们倒杯喝的
Much appreciated.
非常感谢
If you can handle things here,
如果你们能接管这里
we'll be in a scout hut down the next street.
我们就去下一条街那边的侦查屋
Don't worry, we're not sleeping on the job.
别担心  我们不会在执勤时睡着的
After midnight it gets colder than a witch's tit in here.
午夜过后这里会非常冷
'OP17 in...'
17号监控点就...
- 'OP20 in position.' - Received.
-20号监控点就位  -收到
Do you know U2?
U2著名爱尔兰摇滚乐队
- What, the band? - Yeah.
-那个乐队吗  -对
Yeah, course I do. How old d'you think I am?
我当然知道  你以为我有多老
I was massively into them as a kid.
我小时候超级喜欢他们
I saw them at Wembley on The Joshua Tree tour.
我去过他们在温布利举办的《约书亚之树》巡演
That's a good album. I got it on vinyl somewhere.
那张专辑很棒  我应该有一张黑胶版
Right, so, you know the song, Bullet The Blue Sky?
好吧  那你一定知道《射向蓝天》这首歌了
- Yeah. - Well, I had this t-shirt with the lyrics printed on it.
-对  -我有件T恤上印着这歌的歌词
You know, "I can see those fighter planes,"
就是"我看不到那些战斗机"那句
over a picture of a woman screaming.
下面印的是一个怒吼女士的图
I was dead pleased with it.
我非常喜欢那件衣服
You know, it was serious, political.
很严肃  很有政治意义
Yeah. Not "Frankie says relax".
是啊  好过"弗兰基说请放松"
Right. Not "Choose life".
对  也好过"选择生活"
But whenever I wore it my mum would go,
但只要我穿那件衣服  我妈妈就会说
"Can you see those fighter planes yet, Nev?"
"现在你能看到那些战斗机了吗  小内"
That's mums for you, you know.
妈妈们就这样
What made you think of that?
你怎么想起这个了
Dunno.
我不知道
Just...
就...
I never did see any fighter planes, so maybe...
我确实没见过一架战斗机  所以也许...
You got that feeling now, have you?
你现在也有那种感觉  对吗
Yeah. Yeah, I do, guv.
对  我就那种感觉  老大
I mean...
我是说...
..if this doesn't work, then... what then?
...如果这样不起作用  那...之后怎么办
I tell you what.
听我说
When he does show up, we've got him.
只要他出现  我们就能抓到他
He sets one foot on the plot
他只要踏入监控范围
and he'll stick out like a fucking...
就会被被立刻...
All units, all units, from OP6, be aware.
所有人员  所有人员注意  6号监控点报告
We have a male on foot, Lavinia Gardens towards Morton Avenue.
有一名男性  徒步从拉维妮娅花园走向莫顿大道
Dark hoody worn up, no better description, stand by.
深色帽衫套头  暂无更多描述  请待命
He's entering the driveway of number six Lavinia Gardens.
他走进了拉维妮娅花园6号的私人车道
OP4. OP4. Did you receive?
4号监控点  4号监控点  是否收到
'OP4. Received.'
4号监控点收到
Stand by, stand by. He's down the side of a house.
待命  待命  他已经走到房子门前
'Mobiles standing by and ready to deploy.'
行动组待命  随时准备行动
We could be watching him work.
我们可以看他怎么动手
Negative, I repeat, negative, all units are to stand by.
别动手  我重复  不要动手  所有人待命
Shit. What's that, a torch?
可恶  那是什么  手电筒吗
- Should we make a move, guv? - No.
-要行动吗  老大  -不
No, if we blow our cover, then we've blown the op.
不行  如果伪装暴露  也就毁掉了整个行动
Just wait till we're sure it's him.
再等一下  直到确定就是他
Stand down, stand down,
警报解除  警报解除
it's a young white male going home to bed.
只是一个年轻白人男性回家休息
- 'Lucky bastard.' - OP6 out.
-他可真幸福  -6号监控点结束
'Mobiles standing down.'
行动组撤退
You ok?
你没事吧
I'm stiff as a board!
累得我浑身僵硬
I don't know how they do it night after night.
真不知道他们怎么每晚坚持下来的
They sleep in the day, for one.
首先  他们白天会睡觉
Can't you go in later?
你就不能晚点去上班吗
I've got a Health and Safety briefing.
我要参加一个健康安全汇报会
I missed the last two and it's been suggested from above
之前两场我都缺席  上面提醒我
that I might want to start taking an interest.
我最好关注这个方面
- Or what? - I'm not giving them any excuse to take my toys away.
-否则呢  -我不会让他们有借口抢走我的任务
Well, you get killed on the M25,
你要是在M25公路上身亡
they'll be the ones who need Health and Safety.
他们就是要去参加健康安全汇报会的人了
You know, delegation's a hallmark of strong,
特派代表着领导力强而有力
- not weak, leadership. - Louise..
-而不是软弱无能  -路易丝
You're running yourself into the ground.
你这是把自己往绝路上逼
Cos Nathan's away.
因为内森不在
It's possible to care about your job
想在你的工作和生活间
and find... I don't know, balance.
找到...怎么说  平衡  还是有可能的
- Not for me. - How hard have you looked?
-但我不行  -你认真试过吗
That's the way I am, in for a penny, in for a pound.
我就是这样的人  一旦投入  不计安危
I envy people who can leave their work at work.
我羡慕那些能把工作就留在工作场所的人
No, you don't.
不  你才不羡慕
You're gonna be late.
你要迟到了
Yes, I am.
确实
It's watching you these last weeks...
只是  过去这几周观察你...
I know it's been frustrating, nerve-wracking, exhausting...
我知道一直很压抑  紧张  殚精竭虑...
I'm just not sure...
但我不太确定...
I'm just not sure... it's just about catching this man.
我不确定...是只因为要抓住这个人吗
What d'you mean?
什么意思
I think you're going at it this hard
我觉得你这么投入这个案子
because you know it's the last time...
是因为你知道这是最后一次...
..and you're dreading that more than anything.
...而这个事实让你前所未有的害怕
I mean, just look at you.
就看看你自己
You're out all night in the cold
你整晚在外挨冻
and straight back in this morning.
今早还准备正常上班
You don't want to miss a thing, or waste time sleeping,
你什么都不想错过  也不愿浪费时间睡觉
cos you know how big a hole that's gonna leave.
因为你知道退休后心里会有多空虚
And I don't blame you. How could I?
我也不怪你  我怎么会怪你呢
You're in your element, it's just who you are.
这是你最熟悉的事情  你就是这样的人
I just hope when it's over, when you're done...
我只希望当这些都结束  当你退休...
that what we have is enough. That I'm enough.
我们现有的生活能令你满足  我能令你满足
And you can make your peace with pub quizzes and garden centres.
你也能满足于酒吧小游戏和花园中心
Yes to the former, no to the latter.
前半句没问题  后半句不行
Oh, go on, make a joke of it.
好吧  你又要拿这事取笑了
- Unless under duress or in disguise. - Colin.
-除非被胁迫或者假装可以  -科林
You're right.
你说得对
I am scared about what's next.
我很害怕接下来要发生什么
The job's all I know and, to be honest,
我只知道工作  说真的
I can't even imagine what it's gonna be like.
我都不敢想象退休后是什么样
- Right, I'd better go. - We'll be all right, though?
-好了  我得走了  -但我们会没事  对吗
I hope so.
希望如此
We are all set.
我们都准备好了
Observation points will be radioing in any minute.
监控点随时会报告就位
Cheers, Michelle.
谢谢  米歇尔
All right? They let us go a day early.
你们好  他们提前一天放了我们
Oh, yeah? What's that, time off for good behaviour?
真的吗  为什么  表现好的奖励吗
Something like that, yeah.
差不多是这意思  对
- How was it? - Yeah, fine.
-怎么样  -还行
But, erm, you've had a bit of a time of it,
但是  你忙了好一阵了
so I'm relieving you as of now.
所以我现在放你去休息
Oh, no, I appreciate the thought but I'm here now...
不用  好意我心领了  但是我已经来了...
I second that. Do us all a favour and bugger off.
我支持他的决定  拜托就赶紧离开
- Do you want a coffee? - Yeah, please.
-要来杯咖啡吗  -好  麻烦你了
Take tomorrow off, too.
明天也休息吧
It's the weekend, guv.
是周末了  老大
Ok. All right. Yeah. OK, cheers.
好  行  好吧  那谢谢
Anything I should know?
有什么我需要知道的事吗
Er, well, in the increasingly unlikely event
怎么说呢  尽管希望越来越渺茫
that we should actually need to stop someone...
我们似乎都已经没有犯人可阻止了...
Colin Sutton, disillusioned? I don't believe it.
科林·萨顿  大失所望吗  我可不相信
It is essential that we do it
我们一定要注意
as far away from the plot as possible.
逮捕地离监控区域越远越好
Ok...?
好吧
So that if they are ruled out they
这样就算嫌疑人被排除
won't know where they were stopped.
他们也不会知道自己是在哪被盯上的
Less chance of the op and its location leaking?
这样暴露行动和行动地点的可能就会降低
Nice to have you back, Nathan.
你能回来真的太好了  内森
Thank you. Thank you.
谢谢你  谢谢
Good night
晚安
Nine o'clock.
九点钟方向
That's a Zafira, right? Behind that red Citroen.
那是辆赛飞利吗  就在雪铁龙后面
Yeah, that's a Zafira.
对  那是一辆赛飞利
Facelifted model and the colour's right, too.
小改款  颜色也符合
And it wasn't parked there
而且过去两周
or any of the surrounding streets in the last fortnight.
该车没停在那里或附近任何街道上
Call it in.
马上报告
Control, Control from OP6,
控制中心  控制中心  6号监控点报告
can I give a circulation?
我能通报一下吗
'Go ahead, Six.'
说吧  6号监控点报告
We have a grey Zafira
我们发现了辆灰色赛飞利
parked opposite our OP on Lavinia Gardens, facing east.
朝东停在我们哨点对面的拉维妮娅花园
We haven't seen it before.
我们之前从未见过这辆车
It's of the right colour and age to be of interest,
车的颜色和年代都很符合
so can all units please bear this in mind
所以请各部门记住这一点
in case we put it up as moving later?
以防我们随后通报该车动向
All received, OP6. All units, all units, please be aware
收到  6号监控点  全体注意  全体注意
there is a grey Vauxhall Zafira
有辆灰色沃克斯豪尔赛飞利
stationary on Lavinia Gardens, facing east.
朝东停在拉维妮娅花园
It has not been seen previously
该车之前从未出现过
and OP6 will update if there is any movement.
如有任何动作  6号监控点会更新消息
Control out.
控制中心下线
Not even a partial on the reg?
一点车牌都看不到吗
'Sorry, totally blocked from view.'
抱歉  视线完全被挡住了
Someone could stretch their legs, get it that way?
可以让人去现场看看吗
No. Can't risk it. Stay in position.
不行  不能冒险  待在原地
Understood.
明白
- Hello, love. - Hello.
-你好  亲爱的  -你好
- Thought I'd surprise you. - Mission accomplished?
-我以为会给你个惊喜  -任务完成了吗
Nathan finished his course a day early. He insisted.
内森提前一天结束课程  他坚持让我回来
Hope you didn't put up too much of a fight?
希望你们没吵得太厉害
Well, security had to see me out of the building,
警卫不得不把我送出大楼
but apart from that...
但除了那个...
And the Brazil game wasn't any kind of incentive?
巴西队的比赛对你早回来没有吸引力吗
Hadn't even crossed my mind, actually.
实际上  我从未想过这个
- Uh-huh - But, er, if you're game, I am.
-好吧  -但如果你看  我也看
Oh, go on, then.
那就继续吧
Tell Nathan thank you.
替我谢谢内森
Hang on. Got a pedestrian heading east on Lavinia Gardens.
等等  有位行人从拉维妮娅花园向东走来
Make that two pedestrians.
是两位行人
Looks like they're heading for the Zafira.
他们看起来正朝赛飞利走去
No, they've moved past it to an adjacent vehicle.
不  他们经过它上了旁边那辆车
Ok.
好吧
Central 3000 from OP6.
6号监控点呼叫中央3000监控
We've got a sight of the Zafira's plates.
我们看到了那辆赛飞利的车牌
Can we get a PNC vehicle check, please?
能在全国警察电脑系统中查询一下吗
OP6, let me have your warrant number and location.
6号监控点  请告诉我你的执行令号码和位置
3-7-6-4-2-2.
号码是376422
And Lavinia Gardens, over.
在拉维妮娅花园  完毕
Received OP6, go ahead with the index.
收到  6号监控点  请说车牌号
Foxtrot Romeo Zero Six Oscar Bravo Hotel.
车牌是是FRZSOBH
Should be a grey Vauxhall Zafira.
应该是辆灰色沃克斯豪尔赛飞利
OP6 from 3000.
中央3000监控呼叫6号监控点
Indeed it is a grey Vauxhall Zafira,
确实是辆灰色沃克斯豪尔赛飞利
no trace lost or stolen, no reports.
没有丢失或被盗记录  没任何报告
Keeper since new shown as a Jennifer Grant,
最新显示  车主是珍妮弗·格兰特
leased under the Motability Scheme.
车是向"随心行"计划租的
'All received, 3000. OP6 out.'
收到  中央3000监控  6号监控点下线
Motability Scheme?
"随心行"计划吗
Motability Operations Ltd to give them their full title -
全称是"随心行"运营有限公司
based on Southwark Bridge Road.
总部在萨瑟克桥路
Doesn't sound like our man.
听起来不像是我们的人
'Let's try and look on the bright side.
我们还是看看好的方面吧
'It was only 1-0 and England sort of finished strongly.'
比赛结果1比0  英格兰以强劲势头结束比赛
That's what we all say.
大家都这么说
- It was a valiant effort. - They were shocking.
-这是种英勇的尝试  -他们真令人吃惊
One, it's a friendly,
第一  这是场友谊赛
two, you slept through most of it...
第二  你大部分时间都在睡觉
God help us in the World Cup.
希望世界杯我们能争点气吧
Three, it's Brazil, so 1-0 is OK, it's respectable.
第三  那是巴西  1比0还行  很不错了
Lucky it wasn't 5-0.
幸好不是5比0
- Where is the next World Cup? - South Africa.
-下届世界杯在哪里  -南非
- Why don't we go? - Seriously?
-要不我们去吧  -说真的吗
Keep us out of the garden centres.
可以让我们远离花园中心
Got what looks like a Black male
看到一名男性  貌似是黑人
coming up from Lavinia Gardens in a hurry.
正匆忙从拉维妮娅花园走来
He's getting in the Zafira.
他上了那辆赛飞利
I repeat, he's getting in the Zafira!
重复一遍  他上了那辆赛飞利
Adam, you're our closest vehicle. Can you follow?
亚当  你是我们距离最近的车  你能跟上吗
Received. Moving out.
收到  马上出发
He's driving away, heading north on Morton Avenue.
他正驱车沿莫顿大道向北驶去
'Understood. Entering Lavinia Gardens now.'
明白  现在进入拉维妮娅花园
Make sure aerial support get this,
确保空中支援收能到这个
the Zafira is mobile and heading north on Morton Avenue.
赛飞利正在沿莫顿大道向北移动
You're confident he came from Lavinia Gardens?
你确定他是从拉维妮娅花园出来的吗
'Very confident.'
非常肯定
Someone needs to check the street for a break-in.
需要有人去街上看看  是否有入室抢劫
Could be a victim needs our help.
可能有受害者需要我们帮助
OP20, we're at the top end of Lavinia Gardens -
20号监控点  我们在拉维妮娅花园的尽头
consider it done.
我们去
Thanks, OP20, make sure you notify
谢谢  20号监控点  确保通知
the adjacent OP so they can cover.
相邻监控点  让他们可以覆盖监控范围
I have the eye. Suspect vehicle moving north on Morton Way.
我看到了  嫌疑车辆沿莫顿路向北移动
He's moving north on Ambleside Avenue on the elevated section.
他正沿着安伯塞德大道的高架段向北行驶
Adam, you've got the 4-2 coming past you for a closer look.
亚当  有辆摩托车会超过你上前仔细看看
'4-2 to Control. I have the target in sight.
摩托车报告控制中心  我已看到目标
'Hold back in this position.
保持该位置
- 'Heading past for a look now.' - 'Copy that.'
-现在超过去看看  -收到
'Confirmed. Driver is an IC three male, no passengers.'
已确认  司机是名黑人男性  没有乘客
Thanks, copy that.
谢谢  收到
'When shall we pull him, Sir?'
我们什么时候拦下他  长官
'The boss was very clear,
老大的意思很明确
'we pick him up as far from the plot as possible.'
我们在距离监控区域尽可能远的地方逮捕他
- Can you be more specific? - Yes, two miles.
-能再具体些吗  -好的  3公里
We're taking 4-2 and giving you advanced backup.
亚当
Should be with you now.
杰夫
'I'll leave it to you, then. 4-2 out.'
那就交给你了  摩托车离开
Cath. The light.
小凯  那盏灯
Police!
警察
What the fucking going? Come on. That's got to be two miles now.
怎么回事  快点  现在一定有3公里了
Oh, shit. He's turned right. Repeat, he's turned right.
该死  他向右转了  重复一遍  他向右转了
I'm still on him.
我还跟着他
'Yeah, I'll scoot back round and catch you up.'
好的  我迅速掉头回去追你
He's turned into a residential area. What's the plan now, Sir?
他转进一个居民区  现在的计划是什么  长官
Plan hasn't changed.
计划不变
Please wait, repeat wait,
请等待  重复一遍  请等待
until he's two miles off the plot.
直到他驶出监控范围3公里
You have 9-9 tracking you as a fallback.
有架直升机正跟着你作为后备
'3000 from 9-9,
中央3000监控  直升机报告
'can confirm we have target vehicle in sight.'
可以确认我们已经发现目标车辆
Hello? Police, can you hear me?
有人吗  警察  能听见我吗
Do you have an update, Adam?
有什么最新情况吗  亚当
I've turned onto Witham Street. Repeat, east on Witham Street.
我拐入了维瑟姆街  重复一遍  维瑟姆街向东
'I'm back behind you.
我就在你后面
'I know that road, it's all residential.'
我知道那条路  都是住宅
You hear that, Sir? Witham Street's all residential.
听到了吗  长官  维瑟姆街都是住宅
Gonna be tough to follow him without showing up.
跟踪他而不暴露会很难
By the looks of things he could be off to hit a new house,
他看上去可能要去另一栋房子作案
I say we pull him now.
我建议我们现在把他拦下来
- I hear you, Adam. - Cathy just called.
-我明白了  亚当  -凯茜刚刚打电话了
You were right, he broke into a bungalow on Lavinia Gardens.
你说得对  他闯入了拉维妮娅花园的一间平房
- Anyone hurt? - Property was unoccupied.
-有人受伤了吗  -那房子没有人住
'Sir?'
长官
Go, go, go, take him!
上  上  上  抓住他
Received. Gonna move in. Are we covered at the rear?
收到  准备靠近  我们后方有后援吗
'Confirmed. We're covered.'
"确认  有后援"
- Everything all right? - DC Adam Spier.
-有什么事吗  -亚当·斯皮尔警员
- Would you mind telling me your name, sir? - Not the exhaust, is it?
-能告诉我您的姓名吗  先生  -不会是尾气管吧
Your name, please.
您的姓名
Kelvin. Kelvin Grant.
凯尔文  凯尔文·格兰特
OK, can you just turn the engine off and hand me the key?
请关闭发动机把车钥匙交给我
You got some ID on you, Kelvin?
你有身份证件吗  凯尔文
No, sorry.
对不起  没有
Well, it looks like you've got a couple of bank cards down there.
好像你那边有两张银行卡啊
They'll do.
它们就行
- Well, these say Delroy... Grant. - Sure.
-这些上写的是德尔罗伊...格兰特  -没错
My name's Delroy Grant, but everyone calls me Kelvin.
我叫德尔罗伊·格兰特  但大家都叫我凯尔文
Well, what should I call you?
我应该怎么称呼你
Delroy.
德尔罗伊
OK, Delroy, well, if you can stay where you are for me,
好吧  德尔罗伊  请你待着别动
my colleague's gonna take a look in your boot.
我的同事要检查一下你的后备箱
- Is it open? - Yeah, it's open.
-是开着的吗  -开着
- What d'you do for work, Delroy? - I'm a carer.
-你是做什么工作的  德尔罗伊  -我是护工
Oh, right. OK.
是嘛  挺好
And what are you doing out this late?
这么晚你出来干什么
I was waiting outside the Co-op to buy some puff,
我在合作社外面等着想买些烟
but the guy never showed.
可那家伙一直没露面
Adam.
亚当
Would you like to step out of the vehicle, please, Delroy?
请你走出车来  德尔罗伊
Delroy Grant, I am arresting you
德尔罗伊·格兰特  我以涉嫌
on suspicion of rape, burglary and indecent assault.
强奸  入室盗窃和猥亵罪逮捕你
You do not have to say anything, but it may harm your defence
你有权保持沉默  但询问过程中
if you do not mention when questioned
你避而不谈的问题都将在后续的庭审中
something which you later rely on in court.
可能会成为对你不利的证据
Colin Sutton.
科林·萨顿
'Colin, it's Nathan. Looks like we've got him.'
科林  我是内森  看起来我们抓住他了
Fuck. You're joking?
操  你逗我吧
Do you really think I'd joke about something like that
你真觉得我会在凌晨三点
at three in the morning?
开这样的玩笑吗
'No, I suppose not. Are you sure it's him?'
我想不会  你确定是他吗
Well, put it this way,
这么说吧
we recovered his grey top with black stripes
我们从他银灰色的赛飞利上起获了
from his silver-grey facelifted Zafira.
他那件有黑色条纹的灰色上衣
- The Colbridge Road footage? - 'Perfect match,
-科尔布里奇路的那段监控吗  -完全吻合
'plus he had a crowbar and a screwdriver in the boot.
加上他后备箱里有根撬棒和一把螺丝刀
'It's early days,
虽然为时尚早
'but I'd say the latter probably made all those pry marks.'
但我认为那些撬痕正是后者弄出来的
Bloody hell! What's his name?
我的天  他叫什么
Delroy Easton Grant.
德尔罗伊·伊斯顿·格兰特
From a continuity of command angle,
从指挥延续性的角度
it probably makes sense for me to carry it on till morning...
或许由我继续指挥到早上会更合理一些...
Good to see that SIO course wasn't wasted.
很高兴那个高级调查官的课程没有白上
'Yeah, didn't think I'd put it to use quite so soon.'
是啊  没想到这么快我就用上了
This is great work, Nathan, it's great work.
干得漂亮  内森  干得漂亮
Please pass that onto the others for me, will you?
请你替我转达给大家吧
Yeah. Will do.
嗯  我会的
- I'll see you at eight. - 'Yeah. See you then.'
-我们八点见  -嗯  回头见
Who are you kidding?
你和谁讲这么久
We got him.
我们抓住他了
I'll put the kettle on.
我去把水烧上
- 'Simon Morgan.' - It's Colin Sutton.
-西蒙·摩根  -我是科林·萨顿
I'm sorry to call you so early,
抱歉这么早给你打电话
but I wanted you to hear it from me,
但我想亲自告诉你
it looks like we've got him.
看起来我们抓住他了
Simon?
西蒙
'Yeah, I'm still here. Fucking hell.'
嗯  我还在  老天
Yeah, that's what I said.
对  我也是这么说的
One of our OPs on Lavinia Gardens saw...
我们位于拉维妮娅花园的一个监控点发现...
'I'm on my way in.'
我这就过来
OK, I'll fill you in when you get here.
好  等你到了我把情况告诉你
This is the boss, Mr Sutton.
这位我们老大  萨顿先生
Hello, sir.
你好  长官
I'm so pleased to meet you.
真是幸会啊
So what are you, batting or bowling?
你是要击球还是投球啊
You're not into cricket, are you, sir?
你不太喜欢板球吧  长官
- Yeah. - But you still don't play?
-喜欢啊  -但你还是不打吧
I do, as a matter of fact, yeah, occasionally. You?
实际上我打  偶尔打  你呢
Yes, yes, of course I do. Bat and bowl.
打  我当然打了  击球和投球
Oh, good for you. My knees won't let me bowl,
那真不错啊  我的膝盖不允许我投球了
but I can still swing a bat around as well as I ever could.
但我还能像以往一样地挥棒
Well, tell me, sir,
告诉我  长官
what do you think of England's chances in South Africa?
你觉得英格兰在南非的机会怎么样
I think we could do with one more fast bowler
我认为我们可以再加一名快投手
but, er, I think we've got a great chance.
但是我觉得我们有很大的机会
Yeah, man, that's what I've been saying!
没错  我一直也这么说
Just so you're aware, sir,
长官  得告诉你一下
my wife suffers from MS and I'm her primary carer.
我妻子患了多发性硬化症  我是她主要的护工
Obviously, this'll come as a shock to her.
很明显  这会让她受惊
Yeah, I imagine it will.
我想会吧
Well, I just want to make sure she's properly taken care of.
我只想确保她会受到照顾
- I'll be worried otherwise. - Sorry to interrupt.
-否则我会很担心  -抱歉打断一下
Mr Grant, could I have your signature for the DNA sample?
格兰特先生  请您签署一下DNA取样好吗
Prints now, please.
现在去录指纹吧
This way.
这边
- Still doing 'em old school? - Oh, yeah. Can't beat a wet set.
-还用老式的方法呢  -对  还是湿定型好用
I need your right hand, please.
请把右手给我
Don't know why you're bothering,
不明白你为什么要费这个劲
you know I always wore gloves.
你们知道我总是戴着手套
That was an interesting comment you made just now
刚刚你说了句很有意思的话啊
about always wearing gloves.
关于总是戴着手套的那句话
Er, could we get a signature off you,
我们能取一个你的签名吗
just to confirm you made it?
只是确认你说了那句话
Have you had any contact
你今晚是否接触过
with a vulnerable or an elderly person tonight, Delroy?
任何体弱或年长的人  德尔罗伊
There's no-one out there with a broken hip
没有一个屁股摔坏了
who can't get to the phone?
无法拿到电话的人吗
No-one in need of help and attention?
没人需要帮助和注意吗
I haven't visited anyone tonight.
我今晚没见任何人
Very important that you ask
如果你有什么不明白
if there's anything you don't understand, Delroy. OK?
请务必问清楚  德尔罗伊  好吗
- Oh, dear, oh, dear, oh, dear. - What is it, Delroy?
-天呐  天呐  天呐  -怎么了  德尔罗伊
You really want to have a look at my son.
你们最好去调查一下我儿子
Your son?
你儿子
This is hard for me... so hard...
这对我来说很难...非常难
..but given the seriousness of the offences,
但鉴于这些罪名的严重性
I want to make sure you get the right man.
我希望你们能抓对人
His DNA's gonna be the same as mine, or very similar,
他的DNA会跟我的一样  或很类似
plus we're the same height, and he lives in the area.
外加我们身高一致  而且他住在附近
Why did you wait until now to tell us this, Delroy?
你为什么直到现在才告诉我  德尔罗伊
I'm still in a state of shock.
我依然处于受惊状态
- Bullshit. - Yeah, course it's bullshit.
-胡扯  -对  当然是胡扯
Twins can share DNA, but not fathers and sons.
双胞胎的DNA一样  但父子不可能
He's right, though, they can be very similar.
但他说得对  仍然可能很相似
- We need to jump on this? - Yeah, we need to make some calls.
-我们需要查这个吗  -对  我们得打几个电话
Get Patricia to look the son up and we can get a sample.
让帕特丽夏去查儿子  然后我们取样
- Yeah. Will do, boss. - And tell her I want to be there.
-好  立刻去办  老大  -并告诉她我一起去
You didn't hang about.
你可没闲着
- We're sure it's him? - Yeah, I think so.
-我们确定是他吗  -我想是的
- The DNA will confirm. - Was he in the system?
-DNA会确认  -他在系统里吗
TBC - I came straight here. Congratulations.
还不知道  我直接来了这里  恭喜
Your day, your case,
你的大日子  你的案子破了
- I just helped it over the finish line. - Thank you.
-我只是帮忙跨过了终点线  -谢谢
- I'll go check on the team. - Yeah, I'll join you.
-我去看看团队  -好  我也去
- I just wanna see his face. - Sure, yeah.
-我只想看看他的脸  -当然
OK, was he in the system or not?
好吧  所以他在系统里吗
- It's complicated. - He's not kidding.
-很复杂  -他没开玩笑
I had to go and have a lie down when they explained it.
听完他们解释后我不得不去躺会
- That's just you, Kenny. - Go on, Nath.
-只有你这样  肯尼  -说吧  内森
There's a burglary, back in '99 in Bromley.
99年在布罗姆利有一起盗窃
Local police inform the Minstead team,
地方警察通知了米恩斯泰德团队
but they don't think it's Minstead Man.
但他们认为不是米恩斯泰德犯
- Didn't fit the criteria? - No.
-不符合标准吗  -对
So Bromley go ahead and investigate.
所以布罗姆利就自己调查了
Now a neighbour of the victim sees a car
受害者有一个邻居看到一辆车
that she thinks looks suspicious
她觉得有些可疑
and she reports the number.
于是就上报了车牌
They run a trace and it's registered to a Delroy Grant
他们一查发现登记在德尔罗伊·格兰特名字
at an address in Forest Hill.
地址是森林山
They put his name in the PNC.
他们把他名字输入全国警察数据库
It IDs six people of that name.
结果发现有六个名字一样的人
One in Hackney, had a burglary conviction. DNA on file.
一个在哈克尼  有盗窃犯罪史  也登记了DNA
Right. And this sample was compared to our scenes?
好  那这份样本和我们的犯罪现场样本呢
They informed us that Hackney Delroy
他们通知我们说哈克尼的德尔罗伊
wasn't Minstead Man.
不是米恩斯泰德犯
- Sounds straightforward. - Yeah, except somehow that result
-听着很简单  -对  只不过不知为何那份结果
became assigned to Forest Hill Delroy's profile
被登记到了森林山的德尔罗伊档案名下
and a nominal was created on our system.
并在我们的系统里建档了
Their mistake became our mistake?
他们的错误成了我们的错误
Yeah. And it gets worse.
对  而且还没完
A DC from our team went to visit Forest Hill Delroy
我们队里有个警员在去找森林山的德尔罗伊
to check his movements on the night of the burglary.
调查他盗窃案当晚的行踪
Yeah, and...?
嗯  然后呢
He was out and it was never followed up.
他没在家  结果也没再继续跟进了
- And that's the Delroy we just nicked? - Yeah.
-那就是我们抓的德尔罗伊吗  -对
Turn to your right.
转到右侧
If his DNA had been taken,
如果采样了他的DNA
he would have instantly been identified as Minstead Man.
立马就能鉴定出他是米恩斯泰德犯
Christ...
天呐
From that moment on, the name Delroy Grant was ruled out.
从那刻起  德尔罗伊·格兰特这个人就被排除了
Turn to your left.
转向左侧
And he wasn't on the swabbing list?
他也没在取样名单上吗
No, been formally eliminated by DNA.
对  因为之前因DNA错误被排除了
- So you'd never have got him that way anyway? - No.
-所以就算用DNA取样法你们也抓不住他  -对
In 2001, the name Delroy Grant cropped up again
在2001年  德尔罗伊·格兰特这个名字又出现
when someone called the hotline pushing him as a suspect.
当时有人拨打热线  说他是嫌犯
It was after one of those Crimewatch appeals.
那是在《犯罪调查》节目播出后
And the action got binned
但没有采取任何行动
because HOLMES said he'd been cleared by DNA.
因为犯罪数据库说他测了DNA  被排除了
Ten years ago.
十年前
A decade.
十年
How many victims since then?
自那以后有多少受害者
'Delroy Grant Jr?'
小德尔罗伊·格兰特
Come in.
请进
Does, er, anyone live here with you, Delroy?
有人跟你一起住这里吗  德尔罗伊
My mum and my brother. What's this about?
我妈和我哥  什么事
You're not in any trouble. No-one's died, it's nothing like that.
你没惹麻烦  也没有人去世  不是这类事
But we do have some difficult news to share with you.
但我们有些不太好开口的消息要告诉你
Ok...
好
Look, can we sit down?
听着  能坐下吗
Are you familiar with the Night Stalker case, Delroy?
你听说过黑夜狩猎者的案子吗  德尔罗伊
- Yeah, the bloke attacking old ladies? - That's right.
-听说过  袭击老妇人的家伙  -对
Said on the news you arrested someone.
新闻上说你们逮捕了一个人
We have, that's correct.
是的  没错
I'm very sorry to tell you that
我很遗憾地通知你
that man is your father, Delroy Easton Grant.
被逮捕的人是你父亲  德尔罗伊·伊斯顿·格兰特
No.
不
No way. It can't be.
不可能  绝对不是
How...
你们
How sure are you?
你们有多确认
Well, we don't have absolute confirmation yet,
我们还没有百分百的确认
but we wouldn't be here unless we were very sure.
但如果没有极大把握  我们也不会来这里
How often do you see your dad?
你跟你父亲多久见一次
Now and then.
偶尔吧
For a long time we had nothing to do with him.
我们有很长一段时间与他没有来往
"We"?
"我们"
Me, Mum, my brother...
我  我妈  我哥
Why was that?
为什么
Well, he walked out when I was a toddler. Two, I think.
他在我还是小婴儿时弃我们而去  我想是两岁
Yeah.
对
Didn't see him again till I was eight or nine.
直到我8还是9岁才再次见到他
Turned up at the school gates one day
有一天突然出现在学校门外
and promised to take me and my brother swimming at the weekend.
答应要周末带我和我哥去游泳
Mum wasn't keen, but she saw how excited we were
妈妈不太乐意  但她看我们这么期待
and changed her mind.
就改变了主意
I was giddy.
我高兴坏了
Like a... kid on Christmas morning.
就像...圣诞节早晨的孩子
Had my bags packed hours before
我很早就收拾好了的东西
he was supposed to pick me up.
比他预定来接我的时间提前好几个小时
I remember I really wanted to show him my backflip.
我记得自己很想向他展示我的后空翻
Pathetic, really...
真可悲
But he never turned up?
但他没来吗
I didn't see him again till I was in my 20s and...
我一直没再见到他  直到我二十多岁  而且
by then I knew.
那时我已经知道了
- Knew...? - What he'd done to Mum.
-知道什么  -他对我妈干的事
The violence. The beatings.
暴力  殴打
What he'd put her through.
他让她经历的一切
Those poor women...
那些可怜的女人
Who got back in touch, you or your dad?
是谁先联系谁的  你还是你爸
Me.
我
Me and my brother.
我和我哥哥
Someone told us that he'd remarried.
有人告诉我们他再婚了
That his wife had MS and what an amazing husband he was,
他妻子有多发性硬化症  说他是个完美的丈夫
what an amazing carer...
是个体贴的看护
- That must've been difficult to believe? - Yeah.
-你肯定难以相信吧  -对
"This I have to see," I thought. So we go round.
我想着"我得亲眼看看"  所以我们去了
"Hello, Dad. Long time, no see."
"好啊  爸  好久不见"
All true.
都是真的
His wife was sweet, but she needed a lot of care...
他的妻子人很好  但她需要很多照顾
and there he was, providing it.
然后他在那  细心地照顾
Kind, patient, everything organised.
体贴  耐心  井井有条
I didn't begrudge her, how could I? But...
我不嫉妒她  我怎么能呢  但我...
Hard to see.
看着很难受
Something else we need to tell you, Delroy.
我们还要告诉你些其他事  德尔罗伊
We're giving it no credit whatsoever
我们完全不相信
but your father has accused you of committing these crimes.
但你父亲称是你犯下了那些罪行
- What...? - Yeah.
-什么  -对
As Patricia said, we don't believe it for a minute,
就像帕特丽夏说的  我们完全不信
but, er, we will have to eliminate you with a DNA test.
但我们必须通过DNA测试排除你
Sorry, hang on, he said...
抱歉  等等  他说.
The rapes and everything? He said it was me?
强奸和那一切  他说都是我干的
Why would he say that?
他为什么要这么说
Because that's the sort of person he is,
因为他就是这种人
and, from what you're telling us, always was.
而且从你刚才告诉我们的来看  他一直是
- There you go. - Thanks.
-给你  -谢谢
They didn't have any torn avocado, I got you ham and cheese.
他们没有鳄梨泥  我给你买了火腿芝士
There you go.
给
My nan's 92 and still dyes her hair... what's left of it.
我奶奶92岁了依然染发  所剩无几的头发
She said when you get old it's like you lose your identity.
她说当你变老后  似乎就失去了身份
People don't see you, they just see an old person -
人们看不见你  只看到一个老人
grey hair, fawn coat, bad glasses, a sheep in a flock.
白头发  浅色大衣  老花镜  羊群中的一只
That's why this went on so long. Victims were invisible.
所以这案子这么久都没破  隐形的受害者
Yeah, and the rest of us are in denial.
对  但我们其他人却不承认
We all think it won't happen to us.
我们都认为不会发生在自己身上
We'll buck the trend.
我们能逆势而行
Bedpans, false teeth,
便盆  假牙
dementia, Zimmer frame. No way, no thanks. Not us, mate.
痴呆  助行架  不可能  不必了  我们不会
And the way we feed that lie is to ignore them.
而我们助长谎言的方式是忽略他们
I mean, we notice them, but we don't see them.
我们注意到他们  但却视而不见
We don't avert our gaze, but we certainly don't linger
我们不会避开视线  但也绝不会多看一眼
cos they're the future we don't want and can't escape.
因为他们是我们不想要却逃不过的未来
Yeah. It's like we blame them, innit.
对  就像我们在责备他们一般  对吧
Exactly.
没错
And what the fuck does that say about us?
这说明了我们是怎么样的人
You ok?
你还好吗
You said when this was over it would hit me.
你说当这一切结束  会给我重创
Yeah, I did. Come on.
是的  我说过  来吧
- Good news? - Just got the DNA back -
-好消息吗  -DNA结果刚出来
effectively 100% match with all our samples.
既成事实  与我们的所有样本都百分百匹配
Semen from the rapes,
强奸案的精液
saliva from the cheek of the Harness Street victim,
哈尼斯街受害者面部的口水
- the orange juice carton at Colbridge Road... - "Effectively"?
-科尔布里奇路的橙汁盒  -"既成事实"
Well, they word it like this,
他们是这样措辞的
"The DNA taken from Delroy Grant
"德尔罗伊·格兰特的DNA
"is 47.5 septillion times more likely to be linked to the DNA
与其他人相比  有47.5的10的24次方倍几率
"of Minstead Man than an unrelated person."
与米恩斯泰德犯相关"
"Septillion." I like the sound of that.
"10的24次方"  我喜欢这说法
- What about the screwdriver marks? - Definitely his, boss.
-那螺丝刀的痕迹呢  -绝对是他的  老大
As they're present at two of the scenes where we got DNA
因为我们在搜查到DNA的两个现场看到了
and loads of scenes where we didn't,
还有其他没有DNA的现场也有
it links him to literally dozens of offences.
这将他与其他数起案件联系在一起
Has he been confronted with this?
已经告知他这一切了吗
No commented as soon as we started rolling.
我们开始砸证据后  他就一言不发
CPS have given us a slot.
皇家检察署给了我们时间
I say we charge him with as much as possible,
我觉得应该尽可能多的起诉他
never mind "He's going down already."
别管什么"反正他肯定要坐牢了"
Agreed. We get justice for as many victims as we can.
我同意  我们要为尽量多的受害者伸张正义
Let's throw the fucking book at him.
我们从严处置他吧
Do you understand the charges brought against you today?
你理解今天对你提起的这些指控吗
- Yeah, I do. - And how do you plead?
-我理解  -你怎么辩护
Not guilty.
无罪
Mr Grant, you are charged with 22 offences
格兰特先生  你被起诉犯下22起罪行
of the utmost gravity,
而且都是重罪
five of rape, six indecent assaults,
五起强奸罪  六起猥亵罪
and 11 burglaries.
和11起盗窃罪
Notwithstanding that you deny them,
尽管你拒绝认罪
there is, in our opinion, a very high likelihood
但在我们看来  如果被判有罪
that, if convicted, you may well receive a long prison sentence.
你很有可能会被判很长的牢狱之刑
You are remanded in custody to...
你将还押候审  待在...
Belmarsh, Madam.
贝尔玛什  女士
To HMP Belmarsh.
贝尔玛什监狱
Plenty of officers working past retirement age now.
现在很多警察都过了退休年龄后继续工作
Everybody's got to go sometime, though.
但人总有退休的一天
Just saying.
我只是说说
DI up in Kilburn got his bus pass five years ago.
基尔伯恩的督察已经退休后继续工作五年了
- Five years? - Yeah.
-五年  -对
Closed a double murder the other day.
前两天还破了一桩双杀案
I can finish up here if you want to get off.
如果你想走  我可以收拾这里
No, no. You're all right.
不不  你回去吧
- You sure? - Yeah.
-你确定吗  -嗯
- Right. - Nathan?
-好  -内森
Thanks.
谢谢
You let me in when, er, the others weren't so inclined.
你接受了我  当其他人都不怎么情愿的时候
I appreciate it.
我很感激
Thank fuck I did, boss.
谢天谢地我这么做了  老大